Karl Horky

Front-end Engineer

The front-end is important. It is the surface between user and API, between content and search engine, between impression and brand.

I develop compelling, usable experiences spanning these divides.

Why? With quality services, I believe the web has the power to improve quality of life. This is my ambition, what drives me.



Location: Vienna, Austria

Email: karl.horky@gmail.com

Portfolio: http://work.karlhorky.com/ LinkedIn: http://linkedin.karlhorky.com/

Strengths

Semantic HTML OOCSS / LESS Angular JS

Responsive Design Git Single Page Apps

REST Ruby on Rails MVC

PHP Detail Oriented Proficient Communicator

Leadership Agile Methodologies Data Analysis

Experience

SendWithUs

2013 - Present

Developer

Front- and back-end developer on transactional email management web application for marketers. Built with Django and Knockout.js.

2011 - 2013

wollzelle GmbH

Web Developer

Front- and back-end development for some of the world's leading brands such as Gucci and Trodat. Part of projects such as:

- transitioned Guccitimeless.com to new, modern design running on Rails
- rebuilt responsive Wollzelle.com with mobile-optimized UI
- created digital, interactive product manual for Gucci watch with Backbone.js

Lead advances into object-oriented css and responsive styling on the team. Played a part simplifying user experience flows and optimizing code factoring. Synergy as part of an agile team.

MYRA Systems w/ CGI Group

2008 - 2011

Web Developer

Interface design and web development consulting for the B.C. provincial government in Canada for web properties such as:

- https://www.healthlinkbc.ca/
- https://www.bcbedline.ca/
- https://connect.health.gov.bc.ca/

Managed customer relationships with multiple branches of the government and outside contractors. Participated in service-delivery processes for large organizations, such as those found in ITIL. Demonstrated accountability and initiative through formal estimates.

MarketMAX IMS

2008 - 2011

Print Designer, Web Developer

Branding packages including corporate identity design and website development.

Deliverables included:

- print marketing such as business cards
- database-driven web product catalogues
- virtual tour web application
- CMS backends

Education

Universität Wien

2011 - 2012

Niveau B2.2, Deutsche Sprache

Camosun College

2004 - 2006

Diploma, Visual Arts

Computer Master Institute of Technology

2004

Web Development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

Mount Douglas Secondary

2003 - 2004

Programming with C++, Web Development with HTML, CSS, PHP

Languages

English

German